Joseph Sciorra collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Joseph Sciorra collection 1903-2018 1979-2018
AFC 2018/065
Sciorra, Joseph, collector
approximately 22,236 items
54 containers
27 linear feet
46 containers (approximately 14,700 sheets)
14 document files (PPT, DOC): digital
101 photographic transparencies: black and white; 35mm
2979 photographic transparencies: color; 35mm
1183 photographic negatives: black and white; 35mm
925 photographic negatives: color; 35mm
164 photographic prints: black and white; various sizes
886 photographic prints: color; various sizes
319 photograph files (AI, EPS, JPG, TIF, PSD): digital
34 posters
13 sound tape reels: analog; 7 in.
227 sound cassettes: analog
554 audio files (MP3, WAV): digital
16 videocassettes (VHS): analog
84 video files (MOV, MP4, AVI, WVM, IFO, VOB, BUP): digital
71 optical discs (CD-R, DVD-R)
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of fieldwork conducted by Joseph Sciorra and his collected papers and materials, 1980s-2018, relating to Italian American folklife primarily in New York City but also in Italy. Topics include Catholic religious expression and material culture in the form of altars, processions, shrines, social clubs, feasts, games, puppeteering, visual arts, folk poetry, and music.
Provenance
Joseph Sciorra; donation; 2018
Accruals
No accruals expected.
Related Material
Related materials can be found in the Brooklyn Rediscovery Folklife Study Project collection (AFC 2017/035), in which Sciorra contributed fieldwork.
Access and Restrictions
The Joseph Sciorra collection is open to research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Biographical Note
Joseph Sciorra is a folklorist and scholar who is the Director for Academic and Cultural Programs at the John D. Calandra Italian American Institute, Queens College (City University of New York).
Scope and Content
Collection of research, fieldwork, interviews, and other documentation conducted and gathered by Joseph Sciorra, 1980s-2018, primarily relating to Italian American folklife but also to New York City neighborhoods and other immigrant communities. Topics include Catholic religious expression and material culture in the form of altars, processions, shrines, social clubs, feasts, games, puppeteering, visual arts, folk poetry, and music.
Arrangement
The Joseph Sciorra collection is organized into 6 series according to intellectual topics/groupings. Within each series material is arranged alphabetically. The series are titled:
Series 1. Religious feasts and processions/Giglio Feast and other (primarily Italian American) religious feasts and processions
Series 2. Italian American religious expression and material culture
Series 3. Italian American music, theater, poetry, and visual arts
Series 4. Fieldwork and research about New York City neighborhoods
Series 5. Administration, meetings, and professional pursuits
Series 6. Italy and Italian American communities research
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Cooper, Martha; Sciorra, Joseph
Subjects
Crèches (Nativity scenes)--New York (State)--New York.; Emigration and immigration.; Festivals--New York (State)--New York.; Italian American Catholics--New York (State)--New York--Folklore.; Italian Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Parades--New York (State)--New York.; Puerto Ricans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.; Rap (Music)--New York (State)--New York.; Sicilian Americans--Massachusetts--Gloucester--Social life and customs.; Sicilian Americans--New York (State)--New York--Social life and customs.
Places
Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; Brooklyn (New York, N.Y.)--Social life and customs.; New York (N.Y.)--Religious life and customs.; New York (N.Y.)--Social life and customs.
Form/Genre
Field notes.; Manuscripts.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1. Religious feasts and processions/Giglio Feast and other (primarily Italian American) religious feasts and processions, ca. 1903-2018
  Manuscripts, photographic material, moving images and sound recordings documenting the Giglio Feast, an Italian American religious festival and street fair, as well as other religious feasts and processions.
  - Sound recording documentation, ca. 1981-1985, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/1)
  - American St. Cono procession, 1988-2013, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Ann Peluso interview transcript, 1988-1989, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Ann Simoneti, September 8, 1992, AFC 2018/065: SR203; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Article, The Drama Review, ca. 1985, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Articles about Nola and Giglio procession, 1990, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Articles/reviews: Natural History and AFS, 1983-2004, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Artifacts, ca. 1986-1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Astoria Feast, 1983-1995, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Boat, May 7, 1981; Procession of Saint Paulinus, July 8, 1981; Interviews (including with Sammy Iovino), August 7, 1981. Tape 4, May 7-August 7, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR118; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Bronx Giglio, 1984, AFC 2018/065: PH061; 17 slides, color (35mm) (Box 56)
  - Brooklyn Feast - ephemera, souvenirs, flyers, etc., ca. 1987-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Brooklyn Feast - hats and shirts, list of lifts, 1981-1985, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Brooklyn Feast - historic photos, 1/2, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts with 9 photographic prints, black and white (8 are 8x10, 1 is 5x7) (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Brooklyn Feast - historic photos, 2/2, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts with 3 photographic prints, black and white (1 is 5.5x7.5 and 2 are 8x10, 1 of which is severely damaged) (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Brooklyn Feast - historic photos, and articles, 1976-2004, 1 folder of manuscripts with 8 photographic prints, black and white (6 are 4x5; 1 is 5x7; 1 is 8x10); 7 photographic prints, color (1 is 5x7; 6 are 4x6) (Box-folder 1/13)
  - Brooklyn Feast - media, ca. 1982-2018, AFC 2018/065: PH051; 2 slides, color (35mm) (Box 54)
  - Brooklyn Feast - media, 1/3, ca. 1982-2018, 1 folder of manuscripts with 2 photographic prints, color (4x6) (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Brooklyn Feast - media, 2/3, ca. 1982-2018, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 1/15)
  - Brooklyn Feast - media, 3/3, ca. 1982-2018, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Brooklyn Feast - miscellaneous music, 1981-1994, 1 folder of manuscripts with 13 photographic prints, black and white (3.5x5) (Box-folder 45/14)
  - Brooklyn Feast - miscellaneous music, 1981-1994, AFC 2018/065: PH102; 20 film negatives, black and white (35mm) (Box 62)
  - Brooklyn Feast - sheet music, 1/2, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Brooklyn Feast - sheet music, 2/2, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Brooklyn Feast - written testimony, 1982-1983, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Brooklyn Feast programs, 2006, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Brooklyn Feast programs, 1/2, 1962-2014, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Brooklyn Feast programs, 2/2, 1962-2014, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Brooklyn Giglio - measured drawings, frame and face, 1992, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society, 1985-1989, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society - transcript problem, 1987-1992, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society exhibit, 1/2, 1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society exhibit, 2/2, 1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society exhibit materials, 1/2, 1987-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/1)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society exhibit materials, 2/2, 1987-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society Temporary Gallery, Giglio slides, ca. 1980-1983, 1 folder of manuscripts with 7 photographic prints, color (4x6) (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society Temporary Gallery, Giglio slides, ca. 1980-1983, AFC 2018/065: PH032; 172 slides, color (35mm) (Box 50-51)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society - Giglio exhibition, 1/3, 1985-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/4)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society - Giglio exhibition, 2/3, 1985-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/5)
  - Brooklyn Historical Society - Giglio exhibition, 3/3, 1985-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/6)
  - Brooklyn Rediscovery contracts, etc., 1981-1982, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/7)
  - Brooklyn Rediscovery, 1981 notes, handwritten, 1981, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/8)
  - Brooklyn Rediscovery, 1981 notes, typewritten, 1981, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/9)
  - Buster Mirando. 82-5, July 22, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR051; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Buster Mirando. 82-6, July 22, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR052; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Buster Mirando. Tape 3, Tape 6, July 22, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR053; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Buster Mirando (2nd tape). Tape 5, July 22, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR049; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Buster Mirando interview, 1982, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 3/10)
  - Caliento Band (Chicago), 1988 (container images with detailed contents in collection folder), 1988, AFC 2018/065: SR202; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Casate Presenti Nella Citta' di Nola, sec. XV-XVIII, 1979, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/1)
  - Children's boat and Giglio, July 13, 1982; Bamonte, Sarge's house, July 16, July 18, 1982 (Tape 2), July 13-18, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR045; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Children's boat and Giglio, July 13, 1982; Bamonte's, Sarge's house, July 16, July 18, 1982, July 13-18, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR044; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Children's Giglio, July 9, 1981; Questua, July 11, 1981. Tape 8, July 9-11, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR015; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Children's Giglio, July 9, 1981; Questua, July 11, 1981. Tape 8, July 9-11, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR017; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Children's Giglio, tape 7 and 8, July, 1981, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/2)
  - Church/Feast exhibit, 1992-1994, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/3)
  - Conflict and the Religious Processions of Italian Williamsburg, 1986-1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/4)
  - Da Feast! film, 2009, afc2018065_dc051; 8 video files (IFO, VOB, BUP)
  - Da Feast! soundtrack, 2009, afc2018065_dc052; 11 audio files (WAV)
  - Dancing on the Boat, Williamsburg, Brooklyn. Tape 1, July 5, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR119; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - "Dancing the Giglio: Popular Music and Festive Performance" presentations, 1988, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/5)
  - Day of first lift. Mass: 1. People from New Haven, 2. Old lifter-son lifts. Iky Peluso. July 12, 1981. Tape 10, July 12, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR021; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - "The Day We Danced the Saint" (Felix Stefanile), 1983-1991, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/6)
  - Dente family, 1990-2001, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/7)
  - Dente family, 1990-2001, AFC 2018/065: PH001; 1 color slide (35mm) (Box 47)
    photo by Martha Cooper
  - Earl Guirto (?) and Mrs. Guirto (?); Interview of Bronx Giglio people, Frankie, October 21-November 5, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR092; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Eddie Di Domenico, Tuddy Ferrara. Tape 3C, May 14, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR078; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Eddie Di Domenico, Tuddy Ferrara. Tape 3C, May 14, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR079; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - End interviews - Giglio day - Church - Bishop's family, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR126; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Farinaccios, interview. Tape 15, July 29, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR032; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Farinaccios; Sarge Merando, July 29-August 3, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR030; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Farinaccios; Sarge Merando. Tape 16, July 29-August 3, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR033; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Father Vivona interview, 1982, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/8)
  - Father Vivona, JS, MC, and Bamonte's; Buster Mirando. 82-4, July 18-22, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR050; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Father Vivona. Interviewer: Shelley/Martha, Bamonte's; Buster Mirando. Tape 4, July 18-22, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR047; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Feast music/lyric translations, 1992, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/9)
  - Fourteen Stations (of the Cross), ca. 1985-1994, 1 folder of manuscripts with 2 contact sheets, black and white (Box-folder 45/2)
  - Fourteen Stations (of the Cross), ca. 1985-1994, AFC 2018/065: PH090; 78 film negatives, black and white (35mm) (Box 61)
  - Fourteen Stations (of the Cross) - Our Lady of Mt. Carmel Church's Good Friday Procession, Williamsburg, Brooklyn (written on slide sleeve), ca. 1985-1994, AFC 2018/065: PH005; 60 slides, color (35mm) (Box 47)
  - Frank, Fran, and Domenic Leo Grande, 1984-01-25, AFC 2018/065: SR093; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Furthermore (Giglio book), 2004, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/10)
  - Game of Moco before lift; Our lady Mrs. Peluso shrines. Tape 11, July 12-16, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR023; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Gary Spanato, 1983-08-21, AFC 2018/065: SR088; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Gary Spanato, 1983-08-21, AFC 2018/065: SR090; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Gary Spanato, August 21, 1983; N. Jersey Giglio/Shelley (Posen) and Joe (Sciorra), September 3, 1983; Bronx Giglio, September 12, 1983; Mr. Barricelli and Ida Cessa, October 5, 1983, August 3-October 5, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR089; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, July 11, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR040; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR069; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR097; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR098; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR099; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR100; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, 1981-1985, AFC 2018/065: SR105; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio (tail out), 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR125; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Giglio '82 Smith/undressing, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR038; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio '82 Smith/undressing, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR039; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio '82, day 1, Nat Bello; Giglio '82, Phil Manna, music, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR037; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio '82, Smith/undressing, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR067; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio '85 interview. Family of Giovanna U'Stella., July 7, 1985, AFC 2018/065: SR112; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio and gender, 1992-1996, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/11)
  - Giglio and women, 1990-1993, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/12)
  - Giglio bar/Manteo rehearsal; Go car, Williamsburg, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR036; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio Bloomberg radio interview, January 13, 2001, AFC 2018/065: SR208; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio book, 2003-2006, 1 folder of manuscripts with 1 photographic print, color (8.5x11) (Box-folder 4/13)
    - East Harlem Giglio, 2003, afc2018065_dc068; 48 photographs (JPG)
    - East Harlem Giglio/OLMC, 2004, afc2018065_dc069; 186 photographs (JPG)
  - Giglio Boys Club, Columbus Day, 2013-2017, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/14)
  - Giglio church show, ca. 1981-1982, AFC 2018/065: PH055; 221 slides, color (35mm) (Box 54-55)
    mostly by Martha Cooper
  - Giglio copy prints and negatives, undated, AFC 2018/065: PH092; 8 film negatives, black and white (4x5); 90 film negatives, black and white (Box 61)
  - Giglio copy prints and negatives, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts with 4 contact sheets, black and white; 1 photographic print, black and white (8x10) (Box-folder 4/15)
  - Giglio di Sant Antonio, dinner and dance, 1993, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/16)
  - Giglio exhibit brochure drafts, ca. 1989, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Giglio exhibit labels, ca. 1981-1983, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 45/5)
  - Giglio exhibition scripts, 1/2, ca. 1983-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/1)
  - Giglio exhibition scripts, 2/2, ca. 1983-1990, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/2)
  - Giglio feast notebooks and address books, ca. 1983-1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/3)
  - Giglio films: documentation/letters, ca. 1983-1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Giglio films: Dr. Louis C. Barricelli, April 1985; Nat Bellow, April 1, 1985, April 1, 1985, AFC 2018/065: SR108; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio images by Martha Cooper, 1980-1983, AFC 2018/065: PH056; 46 slides, color (35mm) (Box 55)
  - Giglio letters, Shelley Posen, 1983-1989, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/5)
  - Giglio meeting, June 22, 1983; Interview Basti Lifter, June 29, 1983, June 22-29, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR082; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio meeting, June 22, 1983; Interview Basti Lifter, June 29, 1983, June 22-29, 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR083; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio Memories, afc2018065_dc043; 12 audio files (WAV)
  - Giglio miscellaneous, 2003-2005, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/6)
  - Giglio movies, May 15, 1985, AFC 2018/065: SR110; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio music, 1981-1985, AFC 2018/065: SR106; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio music contact sheets, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts with 9 contact sheets, black and white (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Giglio music grant, 1994, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/8)
  - Giglio music negatives, undated, AFC 2018/065: PH093; 330 film negatives, black and white (Box 61)
  - Giglio music photographic prints, undated, 1 folder of manuscripts with 20 photographic prints, black and white (8x10) (Box-folder 5/9)
  - Giglio music slides, undated, AFC 2018/065: PH007; 33 slides, black-and white (35mm) (Box 47)
  - Giglio music. Musical examples - M.A. Thesis Performance Studies Department, October 1987 - Joseph Sciorra. "O'Giglio e Paradiso": Festive and Musical Performance in an Urban Ethnic Community.", AFC 2018/065: SR113; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio notebook/neighborhood notebook, October 16, 1982, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 5/10)
    Written in English and Italian
  - Giglio notes, ca. 1981, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/1)
  - Giglio notes, 1982, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/2)
  - Giglio notes, 1983, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/3)
  - Giglio notes, 1984, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Giglio notes, 1985, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/5)
  - Giglio notes, miscellaneous, ca. 1981-1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/6)
  - Giglio papers - NYU - "Fractured or Whole?," ca. 1983, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/7)
  - Giglio papers - NYU - "O' Giglio e Paradiso," 1982, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/8)
  - Giglio papers - NYU - "A Preliminary History of the Giglio Feast," 1983, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/9)
  - Giglio procession - intro/ending, 1984-1997, 1 folder of manuscripts with 3 photographic prints, black and white (8x10) (Box-folder 6/10)
  - Giglio procession - intro/ending, 1984-1997, AFC 2018/065: PH004; 33 slides, color (Box 47)
  - Giglio promotional materials, 1985-1992, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/11)
  - Giglio related contacts, ca. 1980-1983, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/12)
  - Giglio sheet music (book), ca. 1955-1987, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/13)
  - Giglio slides, undated, AFC 2018/065: PH057; 45 slides, color (35mm) (Box 55-56)
    mostly/all images by Martha Cooper
  - Giglio slides, 1983, AFC 2018/065: PH058; 17 slides, color (35mm) (Box 56)
  - Giglio Society of East Harlem journal, 2006-2007, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/14)
  - Giglio Sunday music; Big lift, Giglio/Sunday, July 7, 1985, AFC 2018/065: SR111; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, '83. Bronx, NJ., 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR101; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, and interviews. Tape 1, July 12, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR121; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Giglio, and interviews. Tape 2, July 12, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR122; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Giglio, day 1, Nat Bello; Phil Manna, misc., 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR064; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, July 11, 1982, July 11, 1982, AFC 2018/065: SR043; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, Shelley (Posen), 1981-1985, AFC 2018/065: SR104; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio, tape 2, July 5, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR120; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Giglio. Tape 1, July 19, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR123; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Giglio. Tape 2, July 19, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR124; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Giglio: Bronx, NJ., 1983, AFC 2018/065: SR072; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Giglio: Symposium on Giglio feast in Nola, 2002, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/15)
  - Gioventu di Sacco; Maria Degli Angeli, 1985-2005, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/16)
  - Gods of the City article, 1999, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 6/17)
  - Harlem-Bronx Feast, 1983-1991, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/1)
  - Heaven Touches Brooklyn in July: a film by Tony Nonno, 2001, AFC 2018/065: MV014; 1 videocassette
    Documentary film published by De Nonno Productions.
  - The Historic 1957 Live Nighttime National Television Broadcast of The Dancing of the Giglio, 1957, AFC 2018/065: MV016; 1 videocassette
    The opening night procession of Our Lady of Mount Carmel, Williamsburg, Brooklyn, NY. Published by the Shrine Church of Our Lady of Mount Carmel.
  - Historic Giglio visual documentation by various photographers, ca. 1903-1985, AFC 2018/065: PH008; 55 slides, black and white (35mm); 39 slides, color (35mm) (Box 47-48)
  - I Gigli a Nola: Smithsonian Institution Human Studies Film Archives, 1986, AFC 2018/065: MV002; 1 videocassette
  - Il Folklore d'Italia, ca. 1950, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 45/12)
  - Interview of Farinaccios. Brother, girlfriend, mother and father, grandmother and grandchildren. July 29, 1981. Tape 15, July 29, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR031; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Interview with Mr. Martello; Joe Sciorra, Giglio (container images with detailed contents in collection folder), June 5, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR204; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Interview, Joseph Iovino, and Sam Cangiano, tape 5, June 17, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR012; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Interview, Joseph Iovino, June 17, 1981; Mr. Sam Cangiano, June 25, 1981, tape 5, June 17-25, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR005; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Interview, Joseph Lovino, tape 4, June 17, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR004; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Italian American feasts, 2004, 1 folder of manuscripts (Box-folder 7/2)
  - James and Joe Nunziata, July 23, 1991, AFC 2018/065: SR200; 1 sound cassette: analog
  - Joe [Sciorra] interview with guys at stand, Brooklyn: includes notes from interview. Tape 3, May 7, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR117; 1 sound tape reel: 7 in., analog
  - Joe Dente Line of March, Giglio, 2005, 1 folder of manuscripts with 34 photographic prints, color (4x6) (Box-folder 7/3)
  - Joe Dente Line of March, Giglio, 2005, AFC 2018/065: PH095; 44 film negatives, color (35mm) (Box 62)
  - Joe Peluso, Children's Giglio and boat,, July 17, 1981, AFC 2018/065: SR028; 1 sound cassette: analog